# **LEMUEL GAVIN G. SARET**

Diliman, Quezon City, Philippines email: lgsaret@up.edu.ph / web: lemuelgavinsaret.netlify.app

## **STATEMENT**

I am currently a graduate student in the National Institute of Physics, University of the Philippines, Diliman, and a member of the Gravity Group led by Dr. Ian Vega. As an undergrad, I spent several years studying the properties of the Alcubierre warp drive, its effects to its immediate vicinity, and the deflection it causes to incoming photons. I wrote my undergraduate thesis and several conference proceedings papers based on this work. As a Master's student, I am focused on gravitational wave physics, particularly the dynamics of extreme-mass-ratio-inspirals.

## **EDUCATION**

2020 - Present Master of Science, Physics

University of the Philippines, Diliman, Quezon City, Philippines

University Scholar, GWA 1.00-1.45 (AY 2020-2021 1st sem and 2nd Sem)

2015 - 2020 Bachelor of Science, Physics

University of the Philippines, Diliman, Quezon City, Philippines

College Scholar, GWA 1.45-1.75 (AY 2015-2016 1st sem and AY 2018-2019 2nd Sem)

Thesis: Photon scattering by an Alcubierre warp-drive space-time

2011 - 2015 High School

Manila Science High School, Taft avenue, corner Padre Faura St., Ermita, Manila

Best in Mathematics award

**PUBLICATIONS** 

L. G. G. Saret and I. Vega, Michael Francis Ian G., Photon scattering by an alcubierre warp

drive, in Proceedings of the 38th International Physics Conference of Samahang Pisika ng

Pilipinas(2020), SPP-2020-5A-09

L. G. G. Saret and I. Vega, Michael Francis Ian G., Energy shifts of photons crossing an

Alcubierre warp drive, in Proceedings of the 39th International Physics Conference of

Samahang Pisika ng Pilipinas (2021), SPP-2021-PC-09

## **CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS**

2019 YITP Asian-Pacific Winter School and Workshop on Gravitation and Cosmology

Yukawa Institute of Theoretical Physics (YITP), Kyoto, Japan. February 11-15, 2019.

2019 37th International Physics Conference of Samahang Pisika ng Pilipinas

Tagbilaran, Bohol. May 29 - June 1, 2019.

2019 1st Gravity Group Workshop

Gravity Group, National Institute of Physics, University of the Philippines, Diliman, June 2019. Participated in a week-long workshop comprised of lectures and coding of General

Relativity topics.

2020 2nd Gravity Group Workshop

Held online last August 10 - 14, 17 - 21, 2020. Organized and participated a two-week

workshop comprised of lectures and coding of General relativity topics.

2020 38th International Physics Conference of Samahang Pisika ng Pilipinas

Held online last October 19 - 23, 2020. Presented and participated in the conference.

2021 39th International Physics Conference of Samahang Pisika ng Pilipinas

Held online last October 20 - 22, 2021. Presented and participated in the conference.

2021 Black Holes Inside and Out Conference

Held online last September 27 - October 1, 2021.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

2014 Bronze Award, International Mathematics Competition

Held in Singapore last August 2014

2015 3rd Place, International Regions Mathematics League

Held in University of Nevada, Las Vegas last May - June 2015

2018 Bronze medal, International Theoretical Physics Olympiad

2018 Accomplished Competitor, University Physics Competition

2015 - 2020 Merit Scholar under the Department of Science and Technology (DOST)

2020 - present Accelerated Science and Technology Human Resource Development Program

(ASTHRDP) Scholar under the Department of Science and Technology (DOST)

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2019 Summer Science Internship Program (SSIP)

Served as a mentor for incoming senior high school students of the Philippine Science High School. Taught topics on Physics and Mathematics and helped develop their own

research project.

2016 -2020 Volunteer tutor for the UP Physics Association (UPPA)

Taught Elementary and Fundamental Physics to non - Physics majors.

2020 - present Mentor for Asian MathSci League, Inc.

Taught competitive math to elementary and high school students and proctored local and

international competitions.

2021 Coach of Philippine Team, International Regions Mathematics League

Facilitated an intensive two-week training program and proctored the competition online.

Swimming Enthusiast's Association (SEA UP)

## OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

2017 - 2019 Service Council Member, Christ's Youth in Action (CYA)

Organized university-wide events and outreaches, and mentored groups of students.

**Alumnus** 

2017 -2018 Vice - president for External Affairs, UP Physics Association (UPPA)

**2019 - 2020** Handled the organization's sponsorships and partnerships on top of organizing college -

wide and university - wide events.

### AFFILIATIONS

Gravity Group, National Institute of Physics Christ's Youth in Action (CYA)

Graduate Student - Researcher Alumnus

Research Interests: Compact Objects, Dynamics of

Extreme - Mass - Ratio - Inspirals

**UP Physics Association (UPPA)** 

Alumnus

**SKILLS AND PROFICIENCY** 

Strong Physics Core Classical Mechanics, Electrodynamics, Quantum Mechanics, Statistical Mechanics,

Mathematical Physics, General Relativity, Astrophysics.

Programming Language Mathematica, Python

**Tools** LATEX, Git, AutoCAD, Canva, Photoshop

Other Skills Oral communication, Writing, Microsoft Office, Google Suite

**Languages** Proficient in English and Filipino